Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to expand our safe system a bit more if you go to level one.
And go to the item folder and just drag in an apple.
Put it on layer 20, all the same layer as your character.
And if I go play, we can see I have five apples.
If I collect this apple, I should have ten apples.
Although if I quit this and then play my game again, the game will not save the I now have ten apples.
So we're going to update our Apple pickup blueprint if we open this up.
When we set the amount of apples that we have when we pick up a new apple, we just want to track in
our player preference and we're going to save this to our save game.
We can do this by dragging it off here and then referencing our saved game reference.
So I'll get the save then drag up here and look for set apples.
And I'm just going to leave all these notes.
And connect this value into here.
By the way, I forgot that I made the original apple variable an integer.
So that's why I made a float in the save game.
But it's fine because both of these variables can hold whole numbers.
So if we just connect from here to here, then to make sure that this is saved, we can drag off our
player, save again and look for see game to slot.
And under slot name type in one and then connect this into here.
And this into here.
So now if I go to compile and play, if I pick up and collect this apple, I now have ten apples.
But if I close this and go play again, I'll start the game with ten apples.
So with that, we have updated the same system for apples.
The next thing we're going to do is update the safe system for our coins.
So if I just close this and go over to my coin pickup blueprint.
Whenever I pick up a new coin, I am going to drag in my VP reference.
And get the same game and our drag up here and look the set points and just break the link here.
And I will connect the notes here.
I'm here.
And then to make sure this is saved, I can drag off here and save game to slot.
And the slot name is one and we can just connect this into here.
And that's into here.
Then we made it so that if the player character has 100 coins, when they pick up a coin, we set them
out of coins that they have to zero and we increase their lives by one.
So we also need to make sure we save this data.
So I'll drag off my player reference and get the player save.
And then from here, I'll drag off and set coins.
And I'm just going to move everything.
So it's a bit more clean to see.
So connect this into here.
And we can just leave these both at zero.
And then I can just drag off here and look for satellites.
And connect this into here and this into here.
And then finally we can just drag off our place safe and look for a safe game to start to make sure
we save this.
And the soccer game is one.
And we can just connect the notes here and here.
Okay, so now I can go compile and save.
And then finally, if my player gets game over, I want to give them three more lives.
So if we go over to the game over Widget Blueprint.
Off of a bank contract.
Before we do anything, I am going to drag up here and look for a load.
Game from slot.
The slot is going to be slot.
Name one and from here we will cost to our player save.
And then I'm going to tell the thief that my plan should have three lives.
So I drive up here and look at set lives and I'm going to type in three.
And then I'm going to save this to my slot one.
Fill up the safe slot.
And under Scott name, let's type in one and connect this into here and this into here.
So now if I go compile and say if, say, my character lost three lives when they go to the game, we
a screen, we're going to give them three more lives to play the game with.
So with this, we have updated our save.
In the next lecture, we're going to create a level unlock system.